

FRONTEND ENGINEER

Details

1201, Tower - 15, Fresco
Apartment, Nirvana Country,
sector 50
Gurgaon, 122001
India
9717527745
mohitmaheshwari1711@gmail.com

Links

Linkedin

Github

website

Skills

HTML5 & CSS 2/3

JavaScript

Typescript

Angular (Web Framework)

React.js (Javascript Library)

Redux

Jest (JavaScript Testing Framework)

Node JS

Docker and K8s

AWS

Profile

Front-End Engineer with over 5 years of experience in JavaScript (ES6) and it's frameworks. Have hands-on experience in web and mobile application development using various technologies like React, Redux, Node, Express, Next JS, Angular and Webpack. Able to self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate in a team setting.

Work Experience

SDE - II, TATA 1mg, Gurgaon

MAY 2022 - PRESENT

- Transformed the PWA application by adopting the async reducers approach, resulting in a remarkable reduction of the app bundle size from 137 Kb to a mere 50 Kb gzipped. This implementation led to a substantial boost in code coverage by almost 25% and decreased LFC by 1 second.
- Created a method similar to "getServerSideProps" in Next JS for 1mg PWA application to seamlessly render a server side rendered page.
- Developed a webpack plugin that removes server side code from client build, there by reducing the size of build by 10%.
- Led the initiative to transition from monolithic architecture to mono-repo architecture, leveraging the turborepo tool; optimized CI/CD pipelines, resulting in a 20% reduction in deployment time and improved overall team productivity.
- Lead an agile team of developers, implementing coding standards and conducting regular code reviews, resulting in a 15% reduction in code complexity and improved overall system performance.

SDE - I, TATA 1mg, Gurgaon

JUNE 2021 - APRIL 2022

- Redesigned company's mobile homepage and product detail page, resulting in
 a 30% increase in user engagement and a 25% decrease in bounce rate over a
 6-month period.
- Streamlined web-view efficiency through the implementation of progressive loading techniques, significantly reducing latency and improving page rendering speed by 30% in regions with limited network coverage.
- Introduced skeletons for web pages to prevent cumulative layout shift (CLS) taking it down to 0.
- Engineered the successful collaboration between cross-functional teams to integrate 1mg with TATA Neu app, driving a staggering increase of 3000 daily orders.
- Analyzed and optimized website performance metrics, resulting in decrease in page load times and a 25% increase in user engagement, driving higher conversion rates and revenue growth.
- Consolidated and maintained technical documentation.
- Wrote test cases for react app using jest in TDD approach.
- Implemented and updated application modules under the direction of Senior Software Developers.

Frontend Engineer, Lattice Innovations, New Delhi

- Developed new web app features, functionality, and capabilities using the Angular 2+ framework.
- Spearheaded requirements gathering and validation for a game-changing external web app, fine-tuning UI/UX aspects to address client needs; facilitated a seamless transition to development phase, minimizing risks, and achieving optimal project outcomes.
- Implemented seamless integration with multiple third-party services and external APIs, leveraging complex libraries like Socket.IO for real-time data visualization; reduced code duplicity and increased project efficiency by 40%.
- Profiling, troubleshooting and bug fixes resulting in system performance and scalability improvements.

Internships

Software Developer Intern, Lattice Innovations, New Delhi

DECEMBER 2018 - JANUARY 2019

- As part of the team, created reusable components and adoptive responsive interfaces.
- Developed UI/UX for the project and contributed to the ceremonies and process (code review).
- Captured the best development practices in the way of a friendly coding standards team of 5 developers resulting in improving code stability.

Education

B.Tech, Amity University, Noida

JULY 2014 - APRIL 2018